By now, you might have noticed that dates are a bit hard to work with.
到目前为止 你可能已经注意到处理日期有些困难
Aggregating by date fields,
按照 date 字段聚合
in particular, doesn't work in a practical way.
实际上是不现实的
It treats each time stamp is unique.
每个时间戳都是独一无二的
When it would be more practical to round to the nearest day,
所以最现实的方法还是将其处理为最近一天
week, or month, and aggregate across that period.
一个星期或一个月 并对此期间进行聚合
Take for example, this sum of standard paper quantities by time period.
举个例子 按时间段计算标准纸总数量
You can see in the results here that this really
你可以看到 这里的结果
isn't any more useful than looking at the raw data.
并没有比原始数据更有用
This aggregates from six 6,912 rows in the raw data down to 6,908.
它只是将原始数据的 6912 行内容聚合至 6908 行
Almost all of the data in this table are unique.
表中所有数据几乎都是唯一的
Good news though, there are plenty of
但是好消息是
special functions to make dates easier to work with.
很多特殊函数可以让你更轻松地处理日期
But before we dig into date and time functions,
我们在深入研究日期和时间函数之前
let's take a look at how dates are stored.
让我们来看看日期的存储方式
If you live in the United States,
如果你住在美国
you're probably used to seeing dates formatted as month-month,
你可能已经习惯于使用 月 日 年 (MM DD YY)
day-day, year-year-year-year, or similar month first format.
或类似月份在前的时间格式
It's a non-convention compared to the rest of the world's standards.
与世界其它标准相比 这是非常规的
Check out the link in the instructor notes below to
查看下面的讲师注释链接
see the most other places in the world follow
可以看到世界上其他大部分地方都习惯使用
a day-day, month-month, year-year-year-year, format.
日 月 年 (DD MM YY) 的格式
This isn't necessarily better or worse, it's just different.
这没有好坏 只是不同而已
Databases do it yet another way.
然而数据库使用的是另一种方法
Ordering from least to most granular part of the date,
按照从大到小的时间排序
year-year-year-year, month-month, day-day.
即 年 月 日 (YYYY MM DD)
This is a very specific utility,
这是一个非常具体的实用工具
and basis of that date sorted alphabetically are also in chronological order.
这种日期格式 按字母排序的日期也按时间顺序排列
In other words, date ordering is the
换句话说
same whether you think of them as dates or as bits of text.
日期排序和文本排序都是一样的
With this example here,
这里有个例子
we can see that the year first way the databases store dates,
我们可以看到 用年份在前的数据库存储日期的方式
is ideal for sorting the way we'll want to retrieve this information in the future.
是理想的排序方式 方便我们在以后检索这些信息
Whether we want the most recent or oldest information,
无论我们想要最新的还是最老的信息
day first and month first date formats sort of funny ways that don't make a ton of sense.
日在前或者月份在前的格式 没有任何意义
Another benefit is the date can easily be truncated in order to group them for analysis.
另一个好处是可以容易地截断日期 便将其分组进行分析
Take the date 2017- 04- 01 12:15:01.
比如 2017-04-01 12:15:01 这个日期
If we want to group that with other events that occurred on the same day,
如果我们要将其与当天发生的其他事件进行分组
we can't do that with the date in its current format.
以当前日期格式无法进行
Grouping now or group by every event that occurred on April 1st,
现在以发生在 04-01 12:15:01 的事件
at 12:15, and 1 second.
进行分组
That won't help us very much.
那对我们帮助不大